A life lived in fear... is a life half lived.
Strictly Ballroom is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Baz Luhrmann.
Brave new steps put Scott's career in jeopardy.
With a new partner and determination, can he still succeed?
Scott Hastings, played by Paul Mercurio.
Fran, played by Tara Morice.
Barry Fife, played by Bill Hunter.
Shirley Hastings, played by Pat Thomson.
Liz Holt, played by Gia Carides.
Les Kendall, played by Peter Whitford.
Strictly Ballroom is a 1992 Australian romantic comedy film directed and
co-written by Baz Luhrmann in his feature directorial debut.
The film is the first in his Red Curtain Trilogy of theatre-motif-related films;
it was followed by 1996's Romeo + Juliet and 2001's Moulin Rouge!
Strictly Ballroom is based on a critically acclaimed stage play, originally set up in 1984 by Luhrmann and
fellow students during his studies at the National Institute of Dramatic Arts in Sydney.
An expanded version of the play became a success at the
Czechoslovakian Youth Drama Festival in Bratislava in 1986.
In 1988, it had a successful season at Sydney's Wharf Theatre, where it was seen
by Australian music executive Ted Albert and his wife Antoinette.
They both loved it, and, when Albert, soon after, set up the film production company M&A Productions with ex-Film
Australia producer Tristram Miall, they offered Luhrmann their plan to transform his play into a film.
He agreed on the condition that he would also get to direct it.
The film explores themes of dance, husband wife relationship,
dancer, parent child relationship, transformation.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.